Wesley Mathew

Senior Civil Engineer

Civil Engineer professional with 10+ years of experience. Successfully solved difficult problems that required adaptation and modification of standard techniques, procedures and criteria and committed to providing high quality service to every project, with a focus on health, safety and environmental standards.

Contact

Address

Vasco Da Gama, Goa, 403802

Phone

+91-8550930414

E-mail

wesley.mathew27@gmail.com

Skills

Proficient in MS Office

MIS & Reports

Excellent Communication skills

Interpersonal skills

Analytical skills

Software

AUTOCAD -2D

MS PROJECT

Work History

2018-09 Current

Senior Civil Engineer

Company: AMs Project Consultants Pvt. Ltd.

Responsibilities:

- Prepare detailed project schedules for construction, restoration and refurbishment projects.
- To own the project implementation on site based on agreed project schedules and specification from conception to completion.
- Work with senior management and other stakeholders to ensure all projects are completed before schedule and of excellent quality.
- To help create, implementation of systems and processes to guarantee cost and timeline efficiencies & reporting practices etc.
- To create periodic reports for various projects and prepare weekly project snapshots and action plan.
- To coordinate and manage Architects, Designers, Consultants, Purchase & Admin personnel, technical teams, Contractors, vendors, supervisors etc.
- Orange and Red flag issues which will impact progress and delivery of project and find mitigations solutions to get project back on track.
- Oversee constructions across sites to monitor compliance with building and safety regulations.
- Coordinate, direct and drive construction workers and contractors.
- Forsee and resolve issues that arise from time to time.
- Assist to maintain an inventory management system.
- Coordinate with all Purchase & Admin personnel, data personnel, contractors, vendors etc.

- Work on continuously improving systems, technology, communication practices etc. to ensure cost savings, highest quality and timely delivery for construction, inventory, logistic operations.
- Analyse, manage and mitigate risks.

2014-03 - Executive-Civil

2018-09 Company: Merck Limited, Usgao, Ponda, Goa

Responsibilities:

- To update and maintain all documents related to building and facility maintenance.
- · Completion of GMP and Safety CAPAs.
- · Support to all safety and GMP audits.
- Responsible for performing allotted responsibilities by following Environment, Health and Safety guideline.
- Coordination with external agencies to carry out AMC's and civil related activities which is allotted time to time.
- · Support to all civil related shutdown works.
- Civil related maintenance and repairs in the Plant.
- Any other activities allotted by the Manager from time to time.

2011-05 - Coordinating Civil Engineer

2014-02 Company: Prime Builders, Vasco da Gama, Goa

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for all assigned ongoing projects and meeting customer requirements.
- Engineering Coordination with Consultants for finalization.
- Ensure timely submission/clarifications for all engineering deliverables to Owner/Consultant/Client for obtaining approval.
- Monitor progress/performance of site teams/contractors in line with Project scope/requirements.
- Participate in progress/design review meetings with Consultant/Client during whole Project life-cycle.
- Executing work under project quality and safety standards with consistent progress rate.

2010-08 - Civil Engineer 2011-04 - RCC Consulta

RCC Consultant - Deepak Ghorpade, Vasco da Gama, Goa

Responsibilities:

- · Design of building structures using AutoCAD.
- Site visits for checking of steel and progress.
- Drafting of drawings on AutoCAD.

Education

2006-08 -	Bachelor of Engineering: Civil Engineering
2010-08	Goa College of Engineering - Farmagudi, Ponda
2011-10 -	MBA: Construction Management
2013-10	IIBM Institute of Business Management - Meerut Delhi
	9

Certifications

2010-07 Computer Aided Designing with AUTOCAD-2D

Accomplishments

"NATIONAL SKILL QUALIFICATIONS FRAMEWORK LEVEL-3"

Cleared the assessment for the role of Maintenance
Assistant - Life Sciences (QP No.- LFS/Q0215) approved by
the Government of India - Ministry of Skill Development &
Entrepreneurship.

"SAFETY IN SCAFFOLDING & WORKING AT HEIGHTS"

One day Workshop organized by Green Triangle Society in association with Inspectorate of Factories & Boilers.